Personal Information 55 27 01 37 24 lagunes.jp@gmail.com 29 years old **Soft Skills** ☐ Business vision ☐ Project manager ☐ Time manager ☐ Excellent written communication ☐ Results Oriented **Customer Centric Hard Skills** Frequentist and Bayesian statistics ☐ Data modeling and analy-☐ Project evaluation and review (PERT) ☐ Economics and Finance Consumer neuroscience ☐ Decision analysis Languages □ Native Spanish Advanced English Basic German **Programming Languages** NetLogo \square R □ Python □ Excel * ROI = Revenue generated by led projects / annualized base salary

Juan Pablo Lagunes Gómez

Behavioral & Data Science Manager | ROI = 39.72%*

Professional resume

I have nine years of experience coordinating and implementing data-driven use cases (statistics, data science, and behavioral science). Currently, I manage teams responsible for providing useful and accurate information for managerial decisions throughout the client's life cycle: cross-selling, adoption, activation, retention, and collection. In 2019 alone, the projects I have led generated more than 22 million pesos in profits for my current employer.

Work Experience

Behavioral Economics Manager

Citibanamex. 2017 - Current

Responsible for planning, coordination and implementation of business cases and A|B testing. Basing decisions on data analytics, business intelligence and behavioral insights. Providing service to all the products, services and channels of the financial group, performing across-enterprise project management, and serving as a catalyst for the implementation of disruptive initiatives.

Control and Risk Review Analyst

Banamex. 2014 - 2017

Established the automation of AML/TF tools through macros, which led to significant FTE reductions. Implemented an imputation method for missing KYC data. Responsible for quality forecasting by general linear model. Also, performed transactional analysis of bank accounts.

Data Analyst

Laboratorio 25. 2013 – 2014

Performed a quantitative educational evaluation for whole Sonora's state, through multilevel modeling. Developed psychometric models through latent trait analysis (IRT), factor analysis, Rasch analysis, and Logistic regressions.

Research Assistant

Instituto Nacional de Neurología y Neurocirugía. 2012 - 2014

Carried out quantitative analysis of brain electrical activity, and analysis of event-related potentials. Executed statistical inference in neuropsychological data. Responsible of databases administration and curatorship.

Academic Training

Master in Data Science

Facultad de Ingeniería –Universidad Panamericana 2019 – 2021

Specialization in Applied Statistics

Instituto de Investigación en Matemáticas Aplicadas y Sistemas – UNAM 2014 – 2016

Degree in Psychology: Cognitive and Behavioral Sciences

Facultad de Psicología –UNAM

High Academic Requirement Program (*PAEA*) class of 2009 – 2013